不错
Nice.
不错，不错
Nice, nice, nice, nice.
你饿吗？
You hungry?
你得过来才能吃到，别装着不感兴趣
You know, you gotta come get it. Don't play hard to get.
你会喜欢的
You'll like it.
是猫肉
It's cat.
给你
There you go.
我不知道…
I don't know what...
留点给早饭
Leave room for breakfast.
电量不足
喂，你好？
Hello?
你好？
求你了，别伤害我
Please. Don't hurt me.
想要什么都可以拿走
Here, take anything you want.
你想要吃的吗？拿着
You want some food? Take it.
- 我不会伤害你- 是吗？
- I'm not gonna hurt you.- Yeah?
上次那个人也这么说的
That's what the last guy said.
你能帮我吗？轮子掉下来了
Could... Could you help me? The wheel came off.
我修不好了
I can't fix it.
也许我行，但我不行
Maybe if I... If I could, but I can't.
没有肥皂的唯一好处
You know, the only good thing about no soap
是你可以从很远就能闻到强盗的味道
is that you can smell hijackers a mile off.
你不得了啊！
I am impressed!
这个人10米以外就闻到了我们！
This man smelled us from 30 feet away!
操！
Damn!
说的是我们很臭吗？
What's that say about our hygiene?
你背包里面是什么？
What you got there in that pack?
什么包？
What pack?
他有枪
He got a gun.
妈的，没装子弹
Shit, it ain't loaded.
他们这些人都不装子弹
They never are.
没错吧，老头？
Ain't that right, old man?
打开包，把东西都倒出来，好好地，慢慢地
Open the pack and tip it out on the road, nice and slow.
没办法这么做
Can't do that.
把他妈的包放下，放在地上
Take off the fucking pack and put it on the ground.
不然要你的命！
Or die!
你在听我说吗？
Are you listening to me?
我现在在听
I am now.
- 好- 你在听我说吗？
- Good.- You listening to me?
- 是的- 很好
- Yeah.- Good.
你手再碰我，就别想再拿回去了
Put that hand on me again,you won't get it back.
你们相信这个该死的家伙吗？
Do you believe this fucking guy?
好吧，你想来硬的
All right, you wanna do it the hard way.
你怎么做到的？
How'd you do that?
他把我的手砍掉了！
He just cut my hand off!
你们都站在那儿干什么？吻他！
What are you standing around for? Kiss him!
他说什么？
What did he say?
他吓坏了
He's in shock.
我想他是想说“杀了他”
I think he meant "Kill him."
我感觉不到我的手，我的手！
I can't feel my hand. My hand.
我告诉过你你拿不回去了
I told you you weren't gonna get that back.
是的，你说过
Yeah, you did.
你是谁？
Who are you?
你的水在哪？
Where's your water?
他们没有水，他们本来想拿你的
They don't have none. They were gonna take yours.
然后吃了你，真的
And then eat you. It's true.
水在车里
It's in the cart.
你不拿走吗？
You're not taking it?
- 你要去哪儿？- 西边
- Where are you going?- West.
- 我能跟你去吗？- 不能
- Can I come with you?- No.
但…
But...
我们今晚会找到住处的
We'll find shelter for tonight.
我的腿还很痛
My legs still hurt.
上帝
God.
不！
No! No!
- 好枪法！- 迈克！不！
- Nice shot!- Mike! No!
- 不！- 抓到她了
- No!- We got her.
亲爱的？过来！
Honey? Come here!
不！不！
No, no.
- 求求你，不要！上帝，不要！
- 待在这儿- Please, don't. Please, God, no!- Stay on the path.
- 住手！- 嘿，伙计们
- Stop!- Hey, guys.
待在这儿，这不关你的事
Stay on the path. It's not your concern.
不！
No!
拜托！
Come on!
待在这儿，这不关你的事
Stay on the path. It's not your concern.
- 我不认识你- 我知道，我不住在这儿
- I don't know you.- I know, I'm not from around here.
你当然不住这儿
No shit you're not from around here.
- 好吧，我不想惹麻烦- 是的
- All right, I don't want any trouble.- Oh, yeah.
好的
Okay.
我只是个顾客，好吧？
I'm just a customer. Okay?
好的
Okay.
对不起，我必须看看你的手
I'm sorry, I gotta see the hands.
我不是歹徒
I'm not one of them.
好的
Okay.
我得从包里拿点东西出来
I'm gonna take something out of my pack.
- 你的手指离开扳机- 好的
- Take your finger off the trigger.- Yeah.
漂亮！那是幻影900，伙计
Sweet! That's a Fathom 900, man.
是吗？
Is it?
我从90年代起就再没见过了
I haven't seen one of those since the '90s.
东部弄到的
Yeah, I got it back east.
- 还能用吗？- 是的，只是需要充电了
- Still work?- Yeah. Yeah. Just need it charged.
你可以办到吗？给我一个…我有连线
Can you do that for me?Give me a... I got cables.
不需要连线，我可以把它连到充电器上
I don't need the cables. I can put a trickle charger on it, though, for you.
很好
Good.
我是说，如果你有钱的话
I mean, if you got the coin.
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
是的，我有，我有一样…
Yes, I do. I got something...
- 好的- 是美国制造
- Okay.- It's American-made.
是的，我有好多这样的东西了
Oh, yeah. I got a whole bunch of these.
- 是吗？- 是的
- Do you?- Yeah.
唇膏如何？你有唇膏吗？
How about ChapStick? You got any ChapStick?
唇膏没有，我有猫油，新鲜的猫油
No ChapStick, no. I got cat oil. Fresh cat oil.
- 不，不- 很好的，有好处
- No, no.- It's good, it's good for the...
- 不- 用起来一样
- No, no.- Works the same way.
玩具呢？你有玩具吗？
What about toys? You got any toys?
不，我不玩…哦，我有…
No, I don't play... Oh, I got...
- 好，好- 我们的鸡做得最好
- Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah.- We do chicken right.
- 好吃到让你舔手指- 是的，没错
- Eh, finger lickin' good.- Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay.
好的，好的
All right, all right, all right.
好的，我要这个和这些
All right, now this, with these.
当然，都给你
Absolutely, those are yours.
好的，给我几个小时
Okay. Give me a couple of hours.
- 给它充上电- 谢谢
- Charge it up for you.- Thank you.
你可以到街对面，在奥芬那里等着
You can wait over there across the street, at the Orpheum.
不，我在这里等
No, I'll wait here.
- 酒吧马上就营业了- 我在这里等
- Bar is about ready to open.- I'll wait here.
你不信任我，是吧？
You don't trust me, do you?
- 我在这里等- 好吧
- I'll wait here.- All right.
墨索里尼
卡内基
Carnegie.
有一队人刚进城，他们给你带了些东西
One of the road crews just pulled into town. They've got something for you.
书？
Books?
一整包的书
Whole bag of them.
告诉他们我现在就想看看
Tell them I wanna see them right now.
- 待着- 没问题
- Stay.- No problem.
快，我们走
Come on, let's go.
我们干得不错
We did good.
里面没有你要的那本？
The one you want, it ain't there?
没有
No.
我就不明白，这么一大堆的书
I just don't understand.That's a shitload of books.
你不需要明白
You don't have to understand.
我明白
有没有我说了算，否则我们做不成朋友
I understand. Leave that to me and we can be friends.
我对你有信心，你会找到的
I have faith in you. You'll find it.
等下，我还弄来这个
Wait. I got this, too.
这可是个好东西
Now, this is a treat.
- 是洗发水- 是吗？
- That's shampoo.- Yeah?
去痛饮一顿吧
Go get slammed.
找些女人
Get some pussy.
都算在我账上，你们可以尽情享受
Everything on me, as much as you and your boys can stand.
然后继续上路
Then go back on the road.
我们会找到你的书
And we'll get you your book.
这一点，我毫不怀疑
Of that I have no doubt.
你派出去找书的人连字都不识
You're sending guys out who can't even read to look for one book.
难怪他们找不到什么
Well, no wonder they never find anything.
是的，我手上只有这些人
Yeah, I use the tools I have at hand.
除非你愿意跟他们一起去？
Unless you'd like to go with them?
怎么处理这些？
What about these?
烧了
Burn them.
街对面的那个地方，他们有水吗？
This place across the street, they got any water?
有，如果你付钱的话
Yeah, if you can pay for it.
这个
Here.
你闻闻
Smell this.
一个手下找到的
One of the road crews found it.
谁知道呢？
Who knows?
也许这是地球上最后一瓶洗发水了
It may be the last shampoo on the planet.
并且是你的
And it's yours.
他们找到你的书了吗？
Did they find your book?
没有
No.
外来的？
Outlander?
让我看看手
Let me see.
- 好的，想喝什么？- 水
- All right, what'll it be?- Water.
那是好东西
That's the good stuff.
我需要使用自己的配量供应，所以不便宜
I've gotta eat into my own ration to sell it, so it don't come cheap.
好的
Right.
再加一倍
Get you maybe halfway.
索拉娜！
Solara!
拿着，把它装满
Take this and get it filled.
等等，你需要这个
Wait. You need this.
你能让一下吗？
Can you please move?
谢谢
Thank you.
那是我的猫
That was my cat.
很漂亮
Fine specimen.
我看见你把它打到吧台下
I saw you knock him off the bar.
不，我只是把它吓走，我并没有真正打它
No. I kind of shooed him,I didn't really knock him.
你吓唬我的猫
You raised your hand at him.
不会再发生了，我向你保证
Won't happen again, I promise you.
嘿，马兹，再来一杯如何？
Hey, Martz, how about another drink?
那只猫在这里两年了
That cat's been coming in here for two years.
它比你更有权力待在这儿
It's got more right to be here than you.
我不想惹麻烦
I don't want any trouble.
真可惜，因为你已经…
Well, that's too bad, 'cause you got...
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
路上残害无辜旅客的凶手
Murderer of innocent travelers on the road.
你会为你所做的一切付出代价的，你知道吗？
You are gonna be held to account for the things you've done, do you know that?
知道吗？
Do you?
好了
It's okay.
我会拿着我的东西离开这里
I'm gonna grab my things and I'm gonna walk out of here.
- 好的- 好吗，兄弟？
- All right.- All right, brother?
好的
Yeah.
好
“土必为你的缘故受咒诅
"Cursed be the ground for our sake.
“地必给你长出荆棘和蒺藜
"Both thorns and thistles it shall bring forth for us.
“因为你本生于土，土归土
"For out of the ground, we were taken. For the dust, we are.
“尘归尘”
"And to the dust, we shall return."
住手！
Stop!
拜托
Please.
瑞德吉！
Redridge!
瑞德吉
Redridge.
你是谁？
And who are you?
无名之辈
Nobody.
我不相信
I doubt that.
你在我酒吧里杀的人，他们才是无名之辈
The men you killed in my bar, now, they were nobody.
- 但你却是个大人物- 他的手没抖
- But you, now.- He ain't got the shakes.
- 他不是食人族- 很好
- He ain't one of them.- Good.
这是一个文明的地方，我们不吃人类
This is a civilized town.We don't eat humans.
大灾难之前的人我们见的不多，现在不是了
We don't see too many people from before. Not anymore.
- 你读书吗？- 每天
- Do you read?- Every day.
很好，对你好，我也是
All right. Well, good for you. Me, too.
很滑稽
You know, it's funny.
像你我这样老的人，我们是未来
As old as we are, people like you and me, we're the future.
你想从我这得到什么？
What do you want with me?
直奔主题！
Straight to the point!
我喜欢！
I like that!
你不仅仅受过教育
You're not just educated.
我没见过像你这样身手不凡的
I never saw anyone handle themselves the way you did.
我不知道你从哪里学到的
但我肯定我能用上你
I don't know where you learned it,but I sure as hell could use it.
这个小地方，只是一个开始
This little town, just the beginning.
我准备扩建它
I'm about to expand.
我需要高手的帮助，我需要像你这样的人
I need expert help. I
could use someone like you.
谢谢，但我不感兴趣
Thank you, but I'm really not interested.
为我工作的人，生活得比任何行者想像的都好
Well, the people who work for me live better than any walker ever dreamed.
问问瑞德吉，问问这些年轻人，谁都行
Ask Redridge here. Ask the boys, anyone.
真正的床，热乎的饭菜，女人
Real beds, hot food, women.
干净的水
Clean water.
你可能会过得更糟，朋友
You could do a lot worse, my friend.
谢谢
Thank you,
但我需要去一个地方
but I got somewhere I need to be.
哪里？
Where?
西边
West.
西边什么都没有
There is nothing west.
有人告诉我不是这样
I've been told different.
谁？
By who?
告诉你
Tell you what.
在这儿过夜，感受一下当地的款待，看看你喜不喜欢
Stay the night. Try a little localhospitality, see how you like it.
我们早上再聊
We'll talk again in the morning.
听我一句，行者，你别无选择
Word of advice, Walker. It's not a choice.
总会有选择
It's always a choice.
有人会整晚待在你房外
There'll be someone outside your room all night
如果你需要什么
if you need anything.
我不需要任何东西
I don't need anything.
说不准
You never know.
这是给你的，是洗漱的水和一些吃的
This is for you. It's some water for washing and some food.
还有点特别的藏品，是这里主人的敬意
Little special reserve, too,compliments of the house.
我需要你接着这个或说点什么
这样我才能找到你
I need you to take this or say something so I can find you.
- 谢谢- 不客气
- Thank you.- You're welcome.
- 你还需要点什么吗？- 不，我很好，谢谢
- Can I get you anything else?- No, I'm fine. Thank you.
你是在战争中失明的，还是因为之后的太阳？
Did you get blinded in the war or by the sun after?
我生来就这样
I was born this way.
我想可能是我幸运，因为在它发生的时候
I think probably I'm lucky, because I was already used to being like this
我就已经习惯这样了
by the time it happened.
是的，谢谢你的食物
Right, well, thank you for the food.
不客气
You're welcome.
我喜欢你的香水
I like your perfume.
不过是洗发水
It's just shampoo,
但是谢谢
but thank you.
晚安
Good night.
我认为他早上是不会改主意的
I don't think he's gonna change his mind by the morning.
他不会留下的
He's not gonna stay.
他跟别人不同
He's different than the others.
你不能像使唤别人那样，使唤他
You're not gonna be able to make him do what you want him to do.
谁说我要出马？
Who said anything about me?
我会派索拉娜去
I'll send Solara.
你不能这么做
You can't do that.
是更好地利用她的时候了
It's about time I got better use out of her.
不要
Don't.
拜托
Please.
求求你，不要，求求你
Please, don't. Please. Please.
求求你！
Please!
我能进来吗？
Can I come in?
等一下
Give me a minute.
已经有人拿来吃的和水
Somebody already came with food and water.
我需要的都有了
I got everything I need.
你确定吗？
Are you sure about that?
这里真的很亮
It's really bright in here.
我是索拉娜
I'm Solara.
是的，你刚在楼下装满了我的水壶
Right. You filled my canteen downstairs.
是的，你是那个行者，对吗？
Yeah. You're the walker, right?
是
Right.
别担心钱，是记在这酒吧的账上的
If you're worried about paying, it's on the house.
付什么钱？
Paying for what?
你为什么不坐下来？
Why don't you take a seat?
不
No.
不，我不能走，我不能，如果我走了，他会伤害我妈妈
No, I can't go. I can't. If I do, he'll hurt my mom.
- 谁？- 卡内基
- Who?- Carnegie.
他是你爸爸？
He's your father?
不，但我们都是属于他的
No. No, but we belong to him just the same.
我会睡在地板上
Look, I'll sleep on the floor.
明天告诉他，你过得很愉快
Tomorrow you can tell him you had a good time.
我向你保证我不会惹麻烦的
I promise you I will be no trouble.
求求你？
Please?
马走到象四
Knight to bishop four.
该你了
Your move.
你多大？
So, how old are you?
什么？
Excuse me?
我只是以前没见过多少
你这个年龄的人路过这里
It's just that I haven't really seen too many people your age come through here before.
自末日
Well, it's been
已经有30个冬天了
30 winters since the flash.
我真的记不清了
I really don't remember.
你记得那时什么样吗？我是说以前的世界
Do you remember what it was like?I mean, in the world before.
是的
Yeah.
那是什么样子？
Well, what was it like?
人们除了必需的，还拥有很多
People had more than they needed.
我们不知道哪些是珍贵的，哪些不是
We had no idea what was precious, what wasn't.
我们扔掉的那些东西现在人们却要争得你死我活
We threw away things people kill each other for now.
- 真的？- 是的
- Really?- Yeah.
你有本书
You have a book.
- 我可以看一下吗？- 不，不可以
- Can I see it?- No, you cannot.
- 我只是想看看- 不，我说过不行
- I just, I just wanna look at it.- No. I said no.
听着，我甚至不识字！拜托，让我看看
Listen, I can't even read! Come on, please, let me just see it.
你至于吗？只是本书！
What is with you? It is just a book!
这不仅仅是一本书
It's not just a book.
- 什么意思，这不只是一本书？- 听着
- What do you mean, it's not just a book?- Look.
不要再问有关书的问题了，好吗？不要再问问题，好吧？
No more questions about the book, all right? No more questions. All right?
既然你在这儿，我有个问题问你
I got a question for you, since you're here.
我或许会回答，或许不
Well, maybe I'll answer it and maybe I won't.
你从哪里弄到水？
Where do you get your water?
不能告诉你
Can't tell you that.
- 你不能告诉我还是你不知道？- 我知道
- You can't tell me or you don't know?- Oh, I know.
但是如果你不告诉我这本书，我就不告诉你水的事
But if you're not talking about the book, I'm not talking about the water.
你真有办法
You're something else, you know.
好吧，我问你另外一个问题
All right, I got another question for you.
好
Right.
你饿吗？
You hungry?
这儿有很多吃的
There's a lot of food there,
我吃不了
more than I can eat.
告诉你
Tell you what.
我们可以一起分享，就像过去老人那样
We can share it, you know,like old people used to.
好
Okay.
好吗？
Okay?
等等，等下，坐下
Wait a minute, wait a minute. Wait. Sit.
坐下
Sit.
这是给你的
This'll be for you.
把手给我
Give me your hands.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
相信我，把手给我
Trust me. Give me your hands.
闭上你的眼睛
Close your eyes.
亲爱的主，感谢你赐给我们食物
Dear Lord, we thank you for this meal.
感谢你赐给我们温暖的床
We thank you for a warm bed
以及在寒冷的夜晚，我们头顶的这项屋檐
and a roof over our head on cold nights such as this.
这些已经久违了
It's been too long.
这是从你书里来的吗？
Is this from your book?
别打乱，闭上你的眼睛
Don't interrupt. Close your eyes.
我们感谢你在这样艰难的时间里
We thank you for the gift of companionship
赐给我们友谊
in hard times like these.
阿门
Amen.
现在可以吃了吗？
Now we eat?
可以了
Now we eat.
早上好，索拉娜
Good morning, Solara.
昨晚如何？你睡得好吗？
How was your night? Did you sleep well?
我按你说的做了
I did like you said.
你当然会按照我说的去做
Of course you did what I said.
但是有用吗？他会留下吗？
But did it work? Is he staying?
我们没聊太多
We didn't do much talking.
索拉娜，亲爱的，吃点东西
Solara, honey, eat something.
妈，把你的手给我
Mom, give me your hand.
闭上你的眼睛
Close your eyes.
妈，相信我
Mom, trust me.
亲爱的主
Dear Lord.
我们感谢你赐予的食物
We thank you for our food.
感谢你赐给我母亲
Thank you for my mother.
感谢你赐给我们屋顶，以及我们的新朋友
Thank you for the roof over our heads and our new friends.
还有…
And...
我想目前就这么多
Well, I guess that's all for now.
阿门
Amen.
这是你要记住的词，阿门
That's the word you're looking for. Amen.
这是结尾
That's how you stop.
你说你们没聊什么
You said you didn't talk much.
那他读了什么没有？
But did he do any reading?
- 我在问你问题- 比尔，别
- I asked you a question.- Bill, don't.
你，闭上你的嘴
You. Shut your mouth.
住手！
Stop!
你在伤害你的母亲，索拉娜
You're hurting your mother, Solara.
他说过他每天都阅读的，是吗？
He said he read every day. Did he?
住手！
Stop it!
你妈妈希望你告诉我
Your mother would like you to tell me.
我不知道！
I don't know!
是的，好的！是的，他在读书
Yes, okay! Yes, yes, he was reading.
- 他读什么样的书？- 我不知道！
- What kind of book was he reading?- I don't know!
- 我不知道！是一本旧皮革的老书- 还有呢？
- I don't know! An old leather one!- And?
我不知道，封面上有些东西
I don't know, it had some kind of thing on the front of it!
- 展示给我看- 你得放了她
- Show me.
- I need you to let her go!
展示给我看！
Show me!
瑞德吉！
Redridge!
妈的！他昨晚整晚都在这儿
Shit! He was here the whole night.
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
我不知…
I don't... I don't...
- 我只想让你务必知道…- 我明白
- I just wanna make sure that you know that...- I understand.
里面没有酸，是沼泽水
...there's no acid in there. That's swamp water.
没关系，把它们拔下来，拔下来
It doesn't matter. Just take these off. Take them off.
- 好的，让我，好的，只是…- 把它们拔下来
- All right. Well, let me, all right, just...- Take them off.
- 嘿！- 好了，可以了，线拆下来了
- Hey!- All right. You got it, coming off.
- 谢谢- 拿下来
- Thank you.- Coming off.
告诉他们是我让你干的，好吗？
You can tell them I made you do it, all right?
好的
All right.
- 说一遍- 你让我干的
- Say it.- You made me do it.
那个家伙上堂了吗？我想它没装子弹
Is that thing loaded? I don't think it's loaded.
只有一个办法能知道
One way to find out.
我需要那本书
Look, I need that book.
我需要那本书，还有你
I mean, I want the book and you,
但是你让我选的话，我会杀了你，拿那本书
but if you make me choose, I'll kill you, I'll take the book.
为什么？你为什么想要书？
Why? Why do you want it?
它陪伴着我长大
I grew up with it.
我知道它的力量
I know its power.
如果你阅读它，你就会有力量
And if you read it, then so do you.
这就是为什么战争后，他们把《圣经》都烧了
That's why they burned them all after the war.
只要活着就是一种信仰行为
Just staying alive is an act of faith.
建造这座城是一种更大的信仰行为
Building this town is an even bigger act of faith,
但是他们不理解
but they don't understand that,
没人明白
none of them.
我没有合适的词句帮助他们，但是这本书有
And I don't have the right words to help them, but the book does.
我承认
Now, I admit
有些事我不得不做
that I've had to do things,
很多我讨厌的事，比如说建这座城，我承认
many, many things, that I hate,to build this. I confess that.
但是如果我们有了那本书
But if we have that book,
我就没必要这样
I wouldn't have to.
想象一下
Now imagine.
如果有正确的词句传播我们的信念，想象一下，会有多么的不同
Imagine how different, how righteous this little world could be
我们的小世界将会有多少正义
if we had the right words for our faith.
人们会真正地明白他们为什么在这儿，他们在做什么
The people would truly understand why they're here and what they're doing
他们不会再需要任何不良的动机
and they wouldn't need any of the uglier motivations.
藏着那本书是不对的，应该和大家一起分享
It's not right to keep that book hidden away. It's meant to be shared with others.
它应该被四处传播
It's meant to be spread.
这难道不是你想要的？
Isn't that what you want?
正是我内心所想
With all of my heart and soul.
我一直都相信
I always believed that
我要找到这本书该归属的地方，一个需要它的地方
I'd find a place where this book belonged, where it was needed.
但是我还没有找到
But I haven't found it yet.
我喜欢这个人
I love this guy.
朝他开枪
Shoot him, please.
你们都站在那里干什么？
What are you standing around for?
杀了他，该死的！杀了他！
Take him out, God damn it! Take him out!
我不喜欢被跟踪
I don't like being followed.
我想和你一起去
I wanna come with you!
不，你不行
No, you don't.
我讨厌这里
I hate it here.
- 那就改变它- 我妈妈认为我跟你一起会更安全
- Then change it.- My mother thinks I'll be safer with you.
我会带你去我们取水的地方
I'll take you to where we get our water.
你能拿多少就拿多少
You can have all that you can carry.
我的意思是，我们能拿多少
I mean, all that we can carry.
卡内基知道北边的另外两处泉水
Carnegie knows about two more springs up north.
他说他会建造更多的城镇
He says he's gonna build more towns.
他是怎么知道这个的？
How'd he know about this one?
他小的时候来过这里
He'd been here when he was young.
在末日之前
In the world before.
我想其他知道这里的人都死了
I guess everyone else who knew about it died.
我们最好快点
We really better hurry.
我想我把太阳镜忘在里面了，你帮我去拿，我在这儿放哨
I think I left my glasses inside. Just take a look for me. I'll look out here.
好的
Okay.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
你这个骗子
You are such a liar!
我不是骗子
I'm not a liar.
你说过如果你拿到水，我就可以跟你走
You said I could come with you if you got your water!
我没说过，是你说的
I didn't say that. You said that.
另外，路上不安全
Besides, the road's no place for you.
比你想象的糟得多
It's much worse than you think.
再见，索拉娜，很高兴认识你，我是诚心的
Goodbye, Solara. It's nice knowing you, I mean that.
- 嘿- 什么？- Hey.
- Yeah?
去你妈的！
Fuck you!
你那他妈的脏手洗过了吗？
Have you washed your filthy fucking hands?
两遍，用肥皂洗的
Twice. With your soap.
叫一队人，我们跟在他后面
Put a crew together. We're going after him.
为了那本他妈的书
For a fucking book.
那不是本他妈的书！
It's not a fucking book!
是武器！
It's a weapon!
一件可以让心灵和思想不再软弱和绝望的武器！
A weapon aimed right at the hearts and minds of the weak and the desperate!
它能让我们控制他们！
It will give us control of them!
如果我们要控制更多的城，我们必须拿到它！
If we wanna rule more than one small fucking town, we have to have it!
人们会聚集到这里
我们让他们做什么，他们都会做
People will come from all over,they'll do exactly what I tell them
如果我们说的话是这本书里的
if the words are from the book.
以前就发生过，以后还会发生的
It's happened before, and it'll happen again.
我们只需要那本书
All we need is that book.
我想要索拉娜
Then I want Solara.
你在跟我讨价还价吗？
Are you bargaining with me?
我们是在这儿做交易吗？
Is this a deal we're making here?
我们失去了很多人手
We lost a lot of men.
你现在更需要我
You need me more than ever.
你说那本书值得为之付出努力，那我相信你
Now, you say that book's worth the trouble. Well, I believe you,
但作为交换，我要索拉娜
but I want Solara for it.
为什么不？
Why not? Why not?
让我们离开这该死的地方
Let's get the fuck out of here.
待在这儿，这不关你的事
Stay on the path. It's not your concern.
我们应该走哪条路？
Which way are we headed?
西边的
West.
喂，你好？
Hello?
可以帮帮我吗？
Can anyone help me?
嘿，有人在吗？
Hello? Is anybody there?
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
是的，我很好，你走吧，我会没事的
Yes. I'm fine. You go along. I'll be okay.
- 不，这里，让我帮帮你- 不用了，谢谢，我真的很好
- No, no, here, let me just help you.- No, really, please. I'm fine. Really.
我需要一个男的来帮我，不是你，你走吧
I need a man to help, not you. You just go along.
- 没关系，几分钟就可以了- 不，没关系
- It's okay, it'll just take a minute.- No! It's fine. Please.
救命！救命！
Help! Help!
放开我！
Get off me!
谢谢！
Thank you!
那边
Over there.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
你听见了？
You hear that?
听见什么？
Hear what?
别动，别动！
Don't move. Don't move.
这里，把弓丝拿下来
Here. Take the wire off of that.
绕到线轴上
Spool it up.
- 那是什么？- 晚餐
- What is that?- Dinner.
感觉好像有什么在保佑他
It's like he's protected somehow,
好像没人可以伤害他
like there's nothing that can touch him.
他只是一个他妈的人
He's just a fucking man.
如果你射他一枪，他会像其他人一样倒下
You put a bullet in him,he'll go down like any other.
还是热的
Still warm.
刚死没几个小时
No more than a few hours dead.
他不可能走远
He can't be far.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch!
索拉娜
Solara.
你确定你还想要她？
Are you sure you still want her?
天快黑了，我们晚上跟踪不了他们，他们会看到我们的
It's gonna be dark soon. We can't track them at night, they'll see us coming.
或许越过了他们，却还不知道
We could drive right past them and never know it.
他是对的
He's right.
他们会走累的，他们需要休息
They're on foot, tired.They'll have to sleep.
我们明天再上路，中午之前就会抓到他们
We'll make up the ground tomorrow.We'll have them before morning's out.
最好万无一失
That better be a guarantee.
你真的每天都读同一本书吗？
Do you really read the same book every day?
无一例外
Without fail.
你会读点儿给我听吗？
Will you read some to me?
可以吗
Please?
“耶和华是我的牧者
"The Lord is my shepherd.
“我必不至缺乏
"I shall not want.
“他使我躺卧在青草地上
"He makes me to lie down in green pastures.
“引我至澄净之水
"Leads me beside the still waters.
“他使我的灵魂苏醒
"He restores my soul.
“以他的名义引导我正义的道路
"He leadeth me in the path of righteousness, for his name's sake.
“我虽然行过死阴的幽谷
"Yea, though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death
“也不怕遭害，因为你与我同在”
"I will fear no evil, for thou art with me."
- 真美- 你喜欢吗？
- That's beautiful.- You like that?
- 是你写的吗？- 是的
- Did you write that?- Yes, I did.
真的？
Really?
不，不是
No, no. No.
它很久以前就有了，比你我来到这个世上都早
No, that was around a long time before you and I got here, that's for sure.
你说它不是普通的书，是什么意思？
What did you mean when you said it's not just any book?
它是唯一的
It's the only one.
真的？
Really?
战争后，人们开始
After the war, people made it their business
寻找并销毁大火中幸存的书
to find and destroy any that the fires didn't get already.
有人说这是导致战争的原因
Some people said this was the reason for the war in the first place.
无论如何，这是唯一保存下来的一本了
Anyway, it's the only one that survived.
你是怎么拿到它的？
How'd you get it?
他们说战争
They said that the war
把天扯开了一个洞，你可能听过这样的故事
tore a hole in the sky, you've probably heard the stories.
是的
Yeah.
天扯开一个洞，太阳可以进来
Tore a hole in the sky, sun came down
烧掉一切
and burned everything.
所有的东西和所有的人
Everything and everybody.
你很幸运在这样的洞里或地下藏起来
You were lucky to hole up and hide in a place like this or underground.
大多数的人就没那么幸运了
Most people weren't lucky.
一年以后，我们从地下出来
So, a year later, we started coming out,
人们徘徊着
and people wandered around.
我不知道要做什么，只想找个地方活下来
I, not knowing what I was gonna do,trying to find a place to survive.
一天，我听到了一个声音
One day, I heard a voice.
很难解释，但它听起来像…
It's hard to explain, but it was like it...
好像从我内心深处发出来的
Like it was coming from inside of me.
但我可以听到它，就好像我听到你跟我说话这样清楚
But I could hear it as clear as I can hear you talking to me now.
那个声音说了什么？
What did this voice say?
它指引我
It led me
去一个地方，我找到了这本书
to a place where I found the book
埋在一些碎石下面
buried under some rubble.
那个声音告诉我把这本书带到西方
The voice told me to carry the book out west.
告诉我有条路会指引我
Told me that a path would be laid out for me,
我会被带到一个使这本书会安全的地方
that I'd be led to a place where the book was safe.
它告诉我，会有人保佑我
Told me that I'd be protected
任何人或事都阻碍不了我前进
against anyone or anything that stood in my path.
我从那时起就一直在走
I've been walking ever since.
你这么做的原因就是因为你听到的一个声音告诉你的？
And you did all that because a voice in your head told you to?
是的
Yes, I did.
我清楚当时我听到了什么
I know what I heard.
我也清楚现在我所听到的
I know what I hear.
我知道我没疯
I know I'm not crazy.
我知道没有他的保佑，我永远不会成功
And I know I would've never made it without help.
- 那是什么？- 太多问题了
- What's that?- One question too many.
睡觉吧，我们早上要很早上路
Go to bed, we got an early start in the morning.
嘿
Hey.
凯马特- 你好，我叫艾利
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
- 抱歉，我以为你在睡觉- 我没睡
- I'm sorry, I thought you were sleeping.- I wasn't sleeping.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
我只是想看看那本书
I just wanted to see the book.
除了我谁也不能碰它，你明白吗？
Nobody touches it but me, you understand me?
你听明白了吗？
Do you understand me?
- 是的，我明白- 好的，去睡觉
- Yes, I understand.- Good. Go to sleep.
你说过你不认识字，它对你没有用
You said you don't know how to read anyway. It's no use to you.
是的
Yeah.
那教我读
So teach me.
等等！停！
Hold up. Hold up! Stop!
你说你已经走了30年了，是吗？
You know, you say you've been walking for 30 years, right?
是的
Right.
你想过你可能迷路了吗？
Have you ever thought that maybe you were lost?
没有
Nope.
你怎么知道你走的方向是正确的？
Well, how do you know that you're walking in the right direction?
“我们行事为人，是凭着信心不是凭着眼见”
"We walk by faith, not by sight."
那是什么意思？
What does that mean?
意思是你知道它是正确的，尽管还没有被证明
It means that you know something,even if you don't know something.
这完全说不通
That doesn't make any sense.
没必要说得通，这是信仰，是信仰
Doesn't have to make sense,it's faith. It's faith.
在一片漆黑里，这是光亮的花朵
It's the flower of light in the field of darkness
给了我前进的力量，你明白吗？
that's giving me the strength to carry on. You understand?
这是书里的？
Is that from your book?
不，是强尼卡什在福尔松监狱的演唱
No, it's Johnny Cash live at Folsom Prison.
什么？
What?
- 你认为有人住在那里吗？- 不知道
- Do you think anyone lives there?- I don't know.
也许那儿有水
Maybe there's water.
待在我后面
Stay behind me.
禁止擅自闯入
这有点奇怪
This is weird.
你们是谁？
Who are you?
我们只是过路的，不是坏人
We're travelers, that's
all. Don't mean any harm.
禁止擅自闯入！你没看到标志吗？
No trespassing! Haven't you read the sign?
对不起，我没看到
We're very sorry. I didn't see it.
你在这儿干什么？
What's your business?
- 是…
- 没事！
- We were just...
- No business!
只是，我们非常抱歉，如果你们允许，我们这就离开
Just... We're very sorry, and if you let us, we'll be on our way.
乔治，看他们，其中一个只是个小姑娘
George, look at them. One of them is just a girl.
是的，老生常谈，我已经听过无数遍了
Yeah. It's an old story, I've heard it a hundred times before.
我们最近很少有访客来，乔治有点疑神疑鬼
We get so few visitors these days.George is suspicious of everybody.
我是玛莎，你们想喝点茶吗？
I'm Martha. Would you care for some tea?
来点音乐如何？旋律很放松
How about some music? It's so soothing.
乔治！
George!
你觉得怎么样？很好听，请喝
How do you like it? It's nice. Please.
- 好喝吗？- 很好，味道很浓郁
- Is that good?- Good, good. That's... Taste is rich.
你们两个能互相依赖活到现在，真了不起
It's amazing that you two have survived out here all by yourselves.
乔治是一个能工巧匠
Well, now, George is something of a handyman.
他为这个地方干了很多活，使这里更安全
He did a lot of work on
this place, making it safe.
我们也许老了，但我们适应性很强
We may be old, but we're resilient.
我们遇到很多人，想从我们这儿抢走这个地方
We've known more than a few who've tried to take this place from us.
- 没错吧，乔治？- 是的，我们遇到过
- Haven't we, George?- Yes, we have.
- 是的- 我给你们看点东西，过来
- Right.- I wanna show you something. Come on.
乔治，别！现在不行！
George, no! Not now!
过来！
Come on!
- 这些是…- 坟墓？当然
- Are these...- Graves? Sure.
不埋葬他们很不文明
Be uncivilized not to bury them.
另外，这对土地有好处
Besides, it's good for the soil.
快进来，我想我可能会给你们做点三明治
Come on back inside. I think I might be able to rustle you up some sandwiches.
谢谢，非常感谢
Well, thank you, thank you very much.
- 得走了- 他们把这些人都杀了
- We gotta go now.- They killed all these people.
不只杀了他们，还吃了他们
They didn't just kill them, they ate them.
- 她的手，她的手在抖- 太多人肉了，我们走
- Her hands... Her hands were shaking.- Too much human meat. Let's go.
我找到了些肉，我想你们饿了
I found some meat. I hope you're hungry.
没有，谢谢
Nope. No, thank you.
我们得走了
Well, we... We gotta be going.
- 这么快？- 是的，很抱歉
- So soon?- Yeah, I'm afraid so.
- 你确定你不留下？- 我肯定，非常肯定
- Are you sure you won't stay?- I'm sure, I'm very sure.
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
索拉娜，你拿着这个，把门打开
Solara, you take this. Open the door for us, please.
- 索拉娜，说感谢你的茶- 感谢你的茶
- Solara, say thank you for the tea.- Thank you for the tea.
非常感谢你的茶
Thank you so much for the tea.
回到里面去
Go back inside.
乔治，怎么了？
George, what's wrong?
一群武装的强盗
Whole company of armed degenerates, that's what's wrong!
他们把他们引到这里
And they led them straight to us.
- 我刚摆好瓷器- 去他妈的瓷器！
- I just set out the good china.- Fuck the china!
你还有其他武器吗？
Have you got any more weapons?
武器？给你看看我的武器
Weapons? I'll show you some weapons.
- 你会开枪吗？- 当然
- Can you shoot a gun?- Of course.
快！快！
Come on, come on!
我们知道你们在里面！
We know you're in there!
出来没人会受伤！
Come on out and nobody needs to get hurt!
我会放你一马！
I'll make it easy!
把索拉娜和书交出来！
Send out Solara with the book!
- 我们怎么办？- 我知道我他妈的在干什么！
- What are we gonna do?- I know what the fuck I'm doing!
- 等等- 我只想要这两样，书和姑娘！
- Wait, wait, wait.- That's all I want, the book and the girl!
他们不会出来
They ain't coming out.
该死！趴下！大家趴下！
Shit! Get down! Everybody, get down!
嘿！你听到的那个声音
Hey! You know that voice you heard?
它有没有告诉你这件事？
Did it say anything about this?
我们会活着出去的，我们俩个！
We'll get out alive, both of us!
那我们呢？
What about us?
没提到你们！
Didn't mention you!
停止开火！
Cease fire!
玛莎？玛莎？
Martha? Martha?
玛莎！玛莎！
Martha! Martha!
- 玛莎- 到边上去！到那边！
- Martha.- Go in on the side! Over on the side!
你们这帮混蛋！
You bastards!
- 在房子的侧面！- 你们他妈的这帮混蛋！
- The side of the house!- You fucking bastards!
- 别开枪！别开枪！- 他们在干什么？
- Hold your fire! Hold your fire!- What are they doing?
没有好事
Nothing good.
书在哪儿？
Where's the book?
看看他的包
Check his pack.
不在这儿
It ain't here.
这是你最后的机会，不交出书，我就把你埋在这儿
This is your last chance. You give it up or I swear I'll bury you out here.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
我们再试试
Let's try this again.
- 卡内基！
- 什么？
- Carnegie!
- What?
书在哪儿？
Now, where's the book?
把书给他吧，拜托
Give him the book, please.
别告诉他
Don't tell him.
在房子里，电视机后面
It's in the house, back of the TV.
检查电视机！
Go check the TV!
什么？
The what?
你他妈的在开什么玩笑！你，去！
You're fucking shitting me. You, go! Go!
无论求什么，只要信，就必得着
Ask, and you shall receive.
上帝是好人，是吗？
God is good, is he not?
一直是
All the time.
不是一直
Not all the time.
不！不！
No! No!
你现在明白了？
You see?
我怎么告诉你的？
What did I tell you?
他只是个人
He's just a man.
不！把他放了！
No! Leave him alone!
求求你，住手！
Please, stop!
你的保护神在哪？
Where's your protection now?
为我祈祷
Pray for me.
可以吗？
Okay?
我认真的
I mean it.
不！
No!
狗屎！
Shit!
回去！
Go back!
快！快！
Come on! Come on!
我们剩的油刚刚可以回去，你想去追她吗？
We barely got enough fuel to make it back. You wanna go after her?
不
No.
- 你要往哪儿走？- 我要去西边，必须去西边
- Where are you going?- I'm going west. Gotta go west.
嘿！
Hey!
来
Here.
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起什么？
For what?
- 这，这都是我的错- 不，不是的
- This. This is all my fault.- No, it's not.
不，是我的错，如果我不跟着你这些就不会发生了
No, it is. If I didn't come with you, none of this would've happened.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
我做了必须要做的事
I did what I had to do.
我认为任何事情都不能使你放弃那本书
I didn't think anything could make you give up that book.
我以为它太重要了
I thought it was too important.
这么多年，我背着它，每天阅读
All the years I've been carrying it and reading it every day.
我只痴迷于想保护它
I got so caught up with keeping it safe,
我忘了靠从中学到的去生活
I forgot to live by what I learned from it.
是的，那是什么？
Yeah, and what's that?
只是…
Just...
帮助他人要多于帮助自己
Do for others more than you do for yourself.
这是我从中学到的
That's what I got from it, anyway.
你闻到了吗？
You smell that?
- 什么？- 空气中的味道？
- What?- In the air?
盐？
Salt?
我们靠近大海了
We're getting close to the ocean.
到了
That's it.
把机械师叫来！
Get the Engineer!
别再靠近！
That's far enough!
你们在这里干什么？
What's your business here?
我叫艾利
My name is Eli!
我有一本英王詹姆士版的圣经
I have a King James Bible in my possession.
待在那里！
Remain where you are!
别试图有什么动作，否则就开枪！
Don't attempt to make any sudden moves, or you will be fired upon!
小心！小心！
Be careful with it. Be careful.
小心
Careful with it.
他们没有武器
They're clean.
我们做这件事已经很久了
We've been doing this for a long time now.
- 感觉像一座博物馆- 不是，比博物馆更好
- Feels like a museum.- No, it's much more than that.
这里是我们重新开始的地方
This is where we're going to start again.
我们有一个印刷机，它很快就可以工作了
We've got a printing press.It'll be operational quite soon.
我们准备教导人们
让他们了解那个失去的世界
We're going to teach people about the world they lost.
帮助他们重建
Help them start to rebuild it.
我是指，你看，莎士比亚大百科全书，只少了几卷
I mean, look. Shakespeare. Britannica,missing only a few volumes.
这是一整套莫扎特和瓦格纳的唱片
There's a whole series of beautiful Mozart and Wagner records
还保存得很好
in still very pristine condition.
但就是没有圣经，不过现在有了
But never a Bible. Well, not until now.
我能问一下它是什么状况？
Well, may I ask what condition it's in?
它很破旧了
It's beat up,
但还能用
but it will do the job.
- 我可以看一下吗？- 是的，可以
- Do you think I could see it?- Yes, you may.
- 好了，打开了- 你打开了吗？
- That's it. It's open.- You there?
你有什么要写的吗？
Do you have anything to write on?
可以给我们一些纸吗？
Could you get us some writing paper, please?
很多纸
And a lot of it.
很多很多
A whole lot of it.
难以置信
It can't be.
这…
It...
这不可能！
It's impossible!
It can't be!
仔细点，记下
Pay close attention and write down
我说的每一句话
everything I say
我说的每个字
exactly as I say it.
“摩西的第一卷书
"The first book of Moses.
“叫《创世记》
"Called Genesis.
“第一章，第一节
"Chapter one, verse one.
“起初
"In the beginning,
“上帝创造天
"God created the heavens
“地
"and the earth.
“第二节
"Verse two.
“地是空虚
"And the earth was without form
“混沌
"and void.
“渊面
"And darkness
“黑暗
"was upon the face of the deep.
“上帝的灵
"And the Spirit of God
“运行
"was hovering
“在水面上
"over the face of the waters.
“第三节
"Verse three.
“上帝说
"And God said,
“要有光
"'Let there be light.'
“就有了光”
"And there was light."
索拉娜在哪？
Where is Solara?
在外面
Out there.
她自己选的
Her choice.
我试图把她带回来，她拒绝了
I tried to bring her back. She refused.
她拒绝后你做了什么？
What did you do when she refused?
- 读- 你对我女儿做了什么？- Read it.
- What did you do to my daughter?
- 读！- 你对我女儿做了什么？- Read it!
你准备好就可以开始了
You can start anytime.
对不起
I'm sorry.
太久了，我不记得了
It's been so long, I don't remember.
- 你必须记得- 必须？是吗？
- You have to.- I have to? Really?
不，你必须记得，拜托
No, no, no, no. You have to. Please.
你的腿
Your leg.
它已经不疼了
It doesn't hurt anymore.
我能闻到
I can smell it.
你为了那本书这么努力
You worked so hard for that book.
你牺牲了这么多人
You sacrificed so much, so many men.
现在连保护你的人都没了
More than you could spare.
以前那些怕你的人，连你的名字都不敢说
Now all those people who were too scared to even say your name,
他们现在就在楼下，正在破坏酒吧呢，你知道吗？
they're downstairs, tearing up the bar right now. Did you know that?
没有人去阻止他们
And there's no one there to stop them.
而你却病了
And you're feverish.
我想象不出那种感受，梦寐以求的书就在眼前
I can't imagine what it must feel like to have what you want so close
- 而你却无从解读它- 闭嘴！
- and it might as well be a million miles away.- Stop it!
你要离开我吗？
Are you leaving me?
克劳迪娅？
Claudia?
克劳迪娅！
Claudia!
走开！
Get away! Get away!
这是我的！
It's mine!
亲爱的主
Dear Lord,
感谢你赐我力量和信念
thank you for giving me the strength and the conviction
去完成你交付给我的任务
to complete the task you entrusted to me.
《创世记》
感谢你在充满荆棘的道路上持续、真诚地指引我
Thank you for guiding me, straight and true, through the many obstacles in my path,
艾利
使我在周围都迷失的情况下，仍然保持坚毅
and for keeping me resolute when all around seemed lost.
感谢你的保护和这一路上的指引
Thank you for your protection and for your many signs along the way.
感谢那些你使我做过的好事，我对我做的坏事感到抱歉
Thank you for any good that I may have done. I'm so sorry about the bad.
你知道你不需要离开，欢迎你留下
You don't have to leave, you know.You're very welcome to stay here.
- 你会非常安全的- 谢谢
- You'll be perfectly safe.- Thank you,
但有些事我必须要做
but this is something that I have to do.
你要去哪？
Where will you go?
家
Home.
感谢你让我结交的朋友
Thank you for the friend I made.
请像照看我那样照看她
Please watch over her as you've watched over me.
感谢你最后允许我安息
Thank you for finally allowing me to rest.
我真的非常累
I'm so very tired,
但是我现在平静地安息
but I go now to my rest, at peace,
因为知道我在这地球上活着的时候所做的是正确的
knowing that I have done right with my time on this earth.
圣经 - 新英王詹姆士译本 阿尔卡特拉斯印刷
那美好的仗我已经打过了
I fought the good fight.
当跑的路我已经跑尽了
I finished the race.
所信的道我已经守住了
I kept the faith.